[KIRKLAND whimpers]
Well? Don't just stand there!
Hurry up and kill him!
Just run him through
with that knife!
[KIRKLAND screams]
No. Mercy, sir!
Why of all people
would you murder me
when I have done nothing to you?
Interesting,
this seems vastly different
from the original plan.
For good reason, no doubt.
You have something else in mind.
Please forgive me, Brother.
This is going to leave you
exposed to public condemnation.
Compared to the burden you're
trying to shoulder alone,
it should be no trouble at all.
The aristocrats on that list
won't be the only
ones who suffer.
After you kill them, numerous
workers will be unemployed.
It's not difficult to
imagine what comes next.
The stampeding proletariat.
[chuckles] Then again, I am
accustomed to dealing with,
shall we say,
those lacking in manners.
The mansion will be in safe
hands with me, Master William.
Grand. See to it,
Jack. Thank you.
[LOUIS]
Why is staying even necessary?
We should leave here and go
into hiding; it would be safer.
[MORAN] Louis, William's
orders are absolute.
I'd strongly advise you
against questioning them.
[WILLIAM]
That's all there is to say.
[WILLIAM] As of now, we're
moving on to the final problem.
What the devil
are you doing here?
I don't remember asking
for any assistance from you.
You killed a man--
you're not in any
position to turn down help.
Why, Sherlock?
Milverton was beyond redemption
and would never
serve a day behind bars.
Someone was bound to do it.
It just happened
to be me. End of story.
And despite knowing
the burden it would
place upon your shoulders,
you did it regardless?
[HOLMES] I was aware of
what it would cost me.
After killing him,
I wouldn't be free to
pursue the Lord of Crime.
Look, Sherly, I'm afraid
if I tell you this,
no good will come of it.
But for better or for worse.
It would appear you've managed
to have gotten away with
committing the perfect crime.
[HOLMES gasps]
You don't mean...?
Are you saying they haven't
recovered his body yet?
[MYCROFT]
Not only that--
there were no
eyewitnesses at the scene,
and because of the fire,
no physical evidence such as
blood traces were left behind.
In short, despite the
statement you made.
You're in the clear.
You cannot be charged for
murder on principle alone.
[LESTRADE]
What do you mean?
In any case, Mary needn't worry
about being threatened anymore.
She and John can
get married now.
So, it all worked out.
[door slams]
[WATSON]
You've some nerve!
[HOLMES]
John.
[WATSON grunts]
[WATSON] Sherlock Holmes
is officially a murderer,
but he wouldn't have been
if he waited for me
like he had promised!
Just how did you
expect me to react?
Thrilled that you murdered
somebody?
[HOLMES gasps]
[HOLMES]
John.
[WATSON] There is a chance
you will be released
without ever having
to go to trial,
but even then, your actions will
haunt you the rest of your life!
You're a criminal,
shackled to the label forever,
and there's nothing you can do.
Reflect on that for
one moment, you jackass!
[HOLMES grunts]
[MYCROFT chuckles]
[knocking]
[POLICEMAN 23A] Inspector.
Forgive me, but it's urgent.
What is it?
[POLICEMAN 23A] Breaking news,
from all the major papers!
The Lord of Crime's true
identity has been revealed!
And on top of that, an official
declaration of responsibility
arrived at the Yard
just moments ago.
[HOLMES grunts]
Well, what did it say?
[WILLIAM]
To all the citizens of England.
This morning, the life of Baron
Herschel was ended by me,
the Lord of Crime,
William James Moriarty.
[WILLIAM]
This is but the beginning.
I hereby declare that I will
slaughter the privileged class
and burn out the rot
that infests this nation.
None will be spared, not a soul.
[WILLIAM] For in truth,
no one can stop me.
[PARLAIMENT 23A]
We demand answers!
Don't just silently
stand there, Lord Moriarty!
[PARLAIMENT 23B]
As head of your family,
you have an obligation
to explain this!
[PARLAIMENT 23C] I'll wager
he had advanced knowledge
of these criminal acts!
[PARLAIMENT 23A]
Say something, Lord Moriarty!
[TOWNSPEOPLE clamoring]
[MAN 23A]
The nobility may be one thing,
but you killed Whitely in cold
blood! He was a decent man!
[MAN 23B]
Send William out, right now!
You've come in vain because
the master is not here!
Now, unless you have
actual business here,
I must ask you to leave!
[MORAN] They're reacting
exactly as predicted.
All of them. Parliament has
denounced the Moriarty name,
while the citizens are
laying bare their anger
at our front gate.
You couldn't ask
for a more ideal start
to the "final problem."
[LOUIS] All this time, I refused
to acknowledge the truth.
The plan only succeeds
with Brother's death
as the grand finale.
[LOUIS] I acted as
though I was unafraid.
I shielded my heart, but now...
[LOUIS] With the moment at hand,
I can no longer pretend.
[LOUIS] Why must you
take this route, William?
Brother, it's unfair you
should offer up your life
on behalf of
an ungrateful world.
They see you only
as a devil, where as I...
You're my world,
all that I have.
[WILLIAM]
Evening, Fred.
When I arrived at the mansion,
all of the servants
had been knocked out.
Your doing, I imagine.
[FRED] Guilty, they only took up
arms at their master's orders.
I don't believe killing
anyone else was necessary.
But if I hadn't done it,
you would've killed them too!
William, I know
you're carrying out
judgment that no one else can!
But at the same time...
You're willing to die to take
responsibility for all of this?
[WILLIAM]
Judgement, you say.
As I'm sure you're well aware,
I don't enjoy smoking.
Filthy habit that
pollutes the lungs.
[WILLIAM] These actions
that I've been undertaking,
I don't consider
them to be just.
If you want the whole truth,
I don't believe a person
has the right to pass
judgement on another.
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
I am staggering
beneath the ever-growing
weight of my sins.
No matter how heinous
my victims may have been.
My hands are stained in scarlet.
[WILLIAM]
And no matter what I do,
nothing will be able
to wash that blood away.
[WILLIAM]
So, you see, my friend.
I'm more than ready to
put an end to all of this.
[FRED] There's no way I can stop
him, at least not on my own.
At this point, all I can
do is appeal to him.
[FRED gasps]
[LOUIS]
Do you intend to betray Brother?
Why?
[LOUIS]
I understand now.
We knew this day would come.
I'll accept any
punishment, except one.
That's the thought
of William dying.
Even more so, the thought
of him wanting to die.
[LOUIS]
I agree with you.
[gasps]
[LOUIS]
I hate to admit it,
but we cannot intervene
without ruining the plan.
With this, it'll be the first
time I've gone against him.
Although,
if there is the slightest
chance of saving William's life.
I'll risk it, even if
it means betraying him.
He mustn't die.
[whimpers]
[GLOVER]
Moriarty!
I-Is anybody out there?
Someone, help me!
[whimpers]
[gasps]
[EVAN, BOY 23A grunting]
You hide behind your children?
Utterly despicable.
Would you dare harm
a defenseless child?
Go right ahead!
[BOY 23A whimpering]
[EVAN whimpers]
Son?
Kill me! Take my life
and spare theirs!
Please, sir, promise me
you won't harm either
my father or my brother!
I beg you!
Please, don't kill them!
[WILLIAM grunts]
[gasps]
[GLOVER groans]
[EVAN gasps]
[EVAN]
No, Father!
You can't die!
[EVAN screams, sobs]
[WILLIAM] Child, you were
bravely willing to sacrifice
your own life to save theirs.
If I deserve to be killed
by anyone, it's by you.
Sadly, that's not to be.
I can't die, at least not
until my work is finished.
I swear, you'll pay
for what you've done.
Moriarty!
[MORAN]
William, at this point,
not even I can pull
the trigger on your behalf.
[MORAN]
No, only one can save you now.
[HOLMES] I see you,
William James Moriarty.
The court ruled in favour
of a child from the slums.
That was Liam, I'm sure of it.
Later, he and his
brother were taken in
by the Moriartys'
eldest son, Albert.
When the estate was set ablaze,
he replaced the
second son, William.
Which means, the three
brothers are the Lord of Crime.
Co-conspirators from the start.
Aboard the Noahtic, I caught
Liam's eye merely by chance.
The Drebber case was a test to
see if I could be of use to him.
[HOLMES] Behind each event
was a hidden agenda.
Liam playing the
role of Robin Hood.
Finally, the dots have
connected in my head.
A single red
thread linking them,
running through
each of the cases!
[HOLMES]
At long last,
I am standing on
the same level as him.
[VICTORIA]
Is that correct?
Even Marquis Glover?
Then it's true,
and the Lord of Crime
is indeed committed
to the destruction
of this country's
privileged class.
Clearly, he wants us to know
nothing will abate his killing.
He can strike anyone,
anywhere, any time.
No one is safe.
We must be quick.
Bring Sherlock Holmes
here at once, Director.
Majesty.
[HOLMES grunts]
I ask your forgiveness, please.
Though it was extreme,
I based my decision
on what I thought
would benefit you the most.
I admit, I wasn't concerned with
the consequences I would face.
But a little more thought--
No.
Much more thought should
have gone into this.
Just as I have a need for you,
I forgot you have a need for me.
As long as we share that bond,
I should be more aware of
how my actions affect you.
From now on, I will
handle myself better.
I promise.
[WATSON]
Look at me.
[gasps]
[WATSON]
Very well.
Now, I have something
to say to you.
I'm thankful... for you
saving Mary and our wedding.
I do mean that, my friend.
John.
Right.
Come now, let's be off.
Her Majesty awaits us.
Imagine, late for the Queen.
Hm?
Before we go, you'll need a tie.
I thank you both for coming.
Our nation is in peril
and needs you.
Mister Sherlock Holmes,
and you, Doctor John
Hamish Watson.
It is an honour to make your
acquaintance, Your Majesty.
[MYCROFT] That was rather
bold of you, Sherly.
Liam risked his life to
create the current situation.
This opportunity
won't come around again.
If things do not change now,
this country of ours
will be finished.
Well, it seems you've finally
realized his intention.
Took you long enough.
[HOLMES gasps]
[HOLMES] It sounds as
though both of us have.
Good-bye.
[MYCROFT] Sherly, don't
get yourself killed.
[HOLMES]
Miss Hudson.
Welcome back home.
We missed you.
[HOLMES]
Too quiet, eh?
[HUDSON giggles]
Ah! Almost forgot; a telegram
arrived for you earlier.
[HOLMES] The third son of
the Moriarty family, Louis.
And you're from the Hope affair,
disguised yourself
convincingly as an old woman.
Your name is?
Fred Porlock, Mister Holmes.
[LOUIS] There's only one reason
I would meet you in this manner.
The truth is--
[HOLMES] You want me to
save Liam's life, correct?
[gasps]
[FRED gasps]
[HOLMES]
In order for Liam's plan
to achieve its maximum effect,
it requires him to die.
Considering the timing and how
you reached out to me directly,
that must mean one thing.
Your brother,
he won't feign his demise.
He truly means to end his life.
Are you going to help us or not?
Answer me!
Rest assured,
I intend to save him.
[LOUIS gasps]
[HOLMES]
After all, Liam is my friend.
As of now, that's all I can say.
Are you satisfied?
[HOLMES]
You've actually reassured me.
There's more to family
than just flesh and blood.
Mister Holmes,
we are more than prepared to
accept any punishment, any.
But please make sure
you save my brother's life.
Leave him to me.
I've come with a request.
Regarding the story of
Sherlock Holmes' nemesis.
Would you kindly
bring it to a close?
As you wish.
[WILLIAM] Next time on
Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The Final Problem, Act Two."